http://www.bmwcca.org/privacy-policy

Login
ActivitiesWhat We DoEventsCalendarAutocrossesCar Control ClinicsConcoursDriving Schools/HPDEsDriving ToursGymkhanasRalliesTire Rack Street SurvivalsTSD RalliesNational EventsMX1 Enthusiast WeekendO'Fest ForeverLegends of the AutobahnFestoricsRaffleRecognition ProgramAwardsAll Award RecipientsClub RacingStaff FormsMembership ContestBenefitsFor MembersBenefits OverviewVehicle RebatesMotorcycle RebateDiscountsForumsClub ServicesOmbudsmenTechnical Service AdvisorsRoundel AppMarketplaceClassifieds & GearStoreClassifiedsChapters68 US ChaptersChapter FinderPolicies & ProceduresChapter ToolboxBMW CCA BylawsBMW CCA Operations ManualBMW CCA Strategic PlanSpecial Interest GroupsNews from NationalRoundelMonthly MagazineArticlesClassifiedsView Roundel OnlineRoundel WeeklyMedia KitiPad & Android AppMediaNews & GalleriesBimmerLifeArchived NewsPhotosVideosMedia KitAboutWho We AreAbout UsContactNational Board of DirectorsNational Office StaffInternational CouncilDriving Events CommitteeHistoryMeeting minutesPolicies & ProceduresBMW CCA BylawsBMW CCA Operations ManualBMW CCA Strategic PlanChapter ToolboxPrivacy PolicyBMW CCA FoundationLinks
Privacy Policy
You are hereHome » About » Policies & Procedures
Last Updated May 24, 2018
The staff at BMW Car Club of America. (“BMWCCA,” “Company,” “we,” “us,” “our”) knows that you care about how your information is collected, used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to learn more about our privacy practices.
WHAT DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVER?
This Privacy Policy applies to https://www.bmwcca.org. This Privacy Policy does not apply to websites, applications or other services that provide their own separate privacy statements or policies. Our Website may contain links to other sites, but BMWCCA is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices of these other sites. Visitors to and users of our Website are referred to individually as “User” and collectively as “Users.”
By visiting or using our Website, you expressly consent to the information handling practices described in this Privacy Policy.
This Privacy Policy covers what information we gather when you are accessing or using our Website, how we use that information and how we protect it. Your use of our Website and information you provide on our Website is subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy.
MINOR'S PRIVACY
Our service is not directed at children under the age of 18. Where we collect information of children under the age of 18 years of age, parents or guardians of these individuals will be required to consent to our collection and use of this information in order for us to deliver services to the individual. For more information about the confirmation process, or how to access your child’s personal data, please use our contact form. Other than as noted, our use of personal information applies to anyone using our services regardless of age. If you are a parent or guardian of an individual under 18, please be sure to read this Privacy Policy thoroughly.
COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION
We gather various types of information from our users and visitors to our site, as explained more fully below. Some of this information is provided directly by you and other information may be gathered by observing how you interact with our Website and Services. We use this information to personalize and improve our services, to allow our users to set up a user account and profile, to fulfill your requests for certain products and services, to analyze how users utilize our Website, and as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy.
Information You Provide
We receive and store any information provided directly by you. For example, we collect personal information such as name, email address, physical address, birth date, zip code, and details of transactions, when provided to us through our Website or when you email our support team directly.
While you can choose not to provide certain information to us, please know that this may result in our being unable to register you or you may be unable to take advantage of some of our features and services.
To remove or update any personal information, please log into your account settings and remove or modify your personal information in the appropriate fields.
Information Collected Automatically from You
Whenever you interact with our Website, we automatically receive and record certain information. This information may include server logs from your browser including your IP address, browser type, internet service provider, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, “cookie” information, and the page you requested.
Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by us and our partners, affiliates, analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering our Website, tracking users’ movements around our Website and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. “Cookies” are small text files stored on a user’s computer or mobile device that allow us to recognize your browser or mobile device and tell us how and when pages on our Website are visited and by how many people. You may be able to change the preferences on your browser or mobile device to prevent or limit your computer or device’s acceptance of cookies, but this may limit you from taking advantage of some of our Website’s features.
Also, if you click on a link to a third-party website, such third-party, for example marketing partners or analytics service providers, may also transmit cookies to you. This Privacy Policy does not cover the use of cookies by any third-parties. These cookies are used to analyze trends and remarket/retarget advertisements to non-converted visitors. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.
When we collect usage information (such as the numbers and frequency of visitors to the Website, the length of stay on the Website, the types of pages visited and other general information), we only use this data in aggregate form, and not in a manner that would identify you personally. For example, this aggregate data tells us how often users use parts of the Website, so that we can make the Website appealing to as many users as possible. We may also provide this aggregate anonymous information to our partners; our partners may use such information to understand how often and in what ways people use our Website, so that they, too, can provide you with an optimal experience.
When you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or "UDID"). We do not ask for, access or track any location-based information from your mobile device at any time while downloading or using our Mobile Apps or Services.
BLOGS, FORUMS AND TESTIMONIALS
Our Website offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your information from our blog or community forum, please use our contact form. In some cases, we may not be able to remove personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us through our contact form.
SOCIAL MEDIA AND WIDGETS
Our Website includes social media features, such as the Facebook button and widgets, such as the Share button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
EMAIL AND OTHER COMMUNICATIONS
We may contact you, by email or other means as you have indicated, to send you information about our products and services, including updates, enhancements, or other related information or to communicate with you about your use of our Website. In addition, where you have agreed, we may send you promotional offers on behalf of other businesses. If you do not want to receive email or other mail from us, please indicate your preference within the account notifications page at https://www.bmwcca.org/manage-account.
WILL BMWCCA SHARE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?
We neither rent, sell nor share your personal information with anyone other than as set forth in this Policy.
We employ third parties (other companies and people) to perform certain tasks on our behalf. These may include use of a payment processor or hosting provider. This may require that we share your information with them in order for us to provide products or services you request. Unless we tell you differently, our agents do not have any right to use the personal information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us.
We may access, read, preserve, and disclose any information that we reasonably believe is necessary to comply with applicable law or court order; to enforce our rights or conditions of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of BMWCCA, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.
BUSINESS TRANSFERS
We may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, customer information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Also, if we (or substantially all of our assets) are acquired, or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or go through some other change of control, personal information would be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by a third party. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Website of any change in ownership or use of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.
Infrequently, BMWCCA permits third parties to have access to member information to provide a benefit. The businesses are carefully selected and are limited to selling products or providing services that augment the lifestyle our members enjoy.
IS MY PERSONAL INFORMATION SECURE?
BMWCCA uses reasonable precautions to protect personal information in its possession from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. For users of our Website, communications between BMWCCA’s site and a user’s web browser are accomplished using, at a minimum, 128-bit Secure Sockets Layer (“SSL”) encryption and various third-party security certificates to protect information. While we endeavor to protect the privacy of your account and other personal information we hold, no method of transmission over the Internet can guarantee complete security. As a result, we cannot guarantee its absolute security despite using commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information.
Your account is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You are responsible for keeping this information secure in order to prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information. When you provide a credit card number, we encrypt the transmission of that information using SSL.
WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION CAN I ACCESS?
Through your account settings, you may access, and, in some cases, edit or delete the following information:
name and password;
email address;
payment information;
user preferences.
The information you can view, update, and delete may change as the Website changes. If you have any questions about viewing or updating your information, please contact us through our contact form. We will respond to your request to access personal information on file with us within a reasonable period of time not greater than 30 days. Please note that you will also be required to authenticate your identity in order to obtain access to any personal information.
WHAT CHOICES DO I HAVE?
You can always choose not to disclose personal information to us, but keep in mind some information may be needed to register with us or to take advantage of some of our special features.
You may be able to add, update, or delete information as explained in the Information You Provide section above.
You may request deletion of your account by contacting us through our contact form. Please note that some information may remain in our systems after you request deletion of the information from your account. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide services. We will also retain and use personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
You may request details of your Personal Information, and where necessary, have it corrected. We reserve the right to charge a reasonable fee to cover our administrative costs for providing you with access to your personal data. For more details, please contact us through our contact form.
FOR USERS OF OUR WEBSITE FROM THE EUROPEAN UNION
Your rights regarding your personal information
The European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation and other data protection laws grant you certain rights in relation to your personal information. Where applicable to you, you can:
request access to your personal information and how we process it
request correction of the personal information that we hold about you
ask us to delete your personal information
object to us processing your personal information
request the restriction of processing of your personal information
request the transfer of your personal information to you or to a third party
withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal information.
Note that withdrawing your consent to our processing of your information will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. You should also be aware that if you do withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain services to you. Where this is the case, we will let you know at the time you withdraw your consent. Please note that even after you have withdrawn your consent we may be able to continue to process your personal information to the extent required or otherwise permitted by law, in particular in connection with exercising and defending our legal rights or meeting our legal and regulatory obligations.
Please also note that in some cases, as we have previously noted within this Privacy Policy, you are able to access, correct and update your personal information directly. Should you need additional assistance, please contact us through our contact form.
CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY
We may amend or update this Privacy Policy from time to time and any such changes or updates will be posted to this Privacy Policy, our Website or other place we deem appropriate so that you are informed as to what information we collect, how we use that information, and under what circumstances we may share that information. If we make material changes in the way we use Personal Information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on our Website or sending you an email prior to the change becoming effective.
About BMW CCA
BMW Car Club of America is the largest single-marque car club in the world.
Copyright © 2014 & All Rights Reserved by BMW Car Club of America
